this is software engineering radio the
podcast for professional developers on
the web at SC - radio dotnet SC radio is
brought to you by the I Triple E
Computer Society I Triple E software
magazine online at computer org slash
software as a software engineer chances
are you've crossed paths with MongoDB at
some point whether you're building an
app for millions of users are just
figuring out a side hustle as the most
popular non-relational database MongoDB
is intuitive and incredibly easy for
development teams to use now with
MongoDB Atlas you can take advantage of
MongoDB flexible document data model as
a fully automated cloud service MongoDB
Atlas handles all the costly database
operations and admin tasks you'd rather
not spend time on like security high
availability data recovery monitoring
and elastic scaling try MongoDB Atlas
for free today
visit MongoDB comm slash cloud to learn
more welcome to software engineering
radio I'm your host Gavin Henry and
today my guest is Neil Madden the o
Madden is the security director for Fort
Rock previously he was the security
architect an engineering for Ford
rocks flagship poopin a.m. access
management product he has a PhD in
computer science as the author of the
upcoming book PPI security in action
from Manning Neil welcome to software
engineering radio is there anything I
missed in your bio that you'd like to
add no that's great and it's good to be
here excellent during the show we will
be talking about API security my
previous show episode 376 API security
with OAuth 2 with Justin richer is out
now so I won't focus too much on
authorization and authentication but it
will be mentioned I'd like to start the
show with an overview of what an API is
and why it should be secured and then go
through a few examples so what is an API
Niall ok so an API is when it stands for
application programming interface and
traditionally the interface between a
library and a napkin
so libraries providing some
functionality and then it makes some set
of functions available to an application
so in terms of API security and what
we're talking about these days most
often are remotely accessible API so
usually REST API is available over HTTP
or over a similar protocol such as G RPC
and so in the context of security then
we're talking about how to kind of lock
down down those API so that only
authorized people can perform actions
using those api's and that the the data
stored and provided access to by those
API is is kind of kept confidential and
only reveal to parties that are allowed
to have access ok and you've got
different types of people for example
that are using API it could be a person
or a program or another machine intern
in a machine to machine type API usage
right exactly so this is one of the
things we cover in my book is that
there's lots of different clients for an
API now so you have sort of traditional
web browser-based clients where the API
might be working a lot like additional
web application and then you have you
know mobile clients you have other
services that might be calling it so
particularly in a Microsoft architecture
you have lots of services calling each
other through api's and now we've got
things like the Internet of Things where
you've got devices out in the physical
world but a calling back to API is in
the cloud or calling API is even on
other devices
yes our user might be a thing but it
might be consuming its own API as well
right has an external facing ok it's Eve
touched a little bit more API security
is so that could be the initial sort of
transport security it could be
protecting the backend resources that
type of thing correct yeah so there's a
bunch of different things we you think
about here so there's the kind of
connection between the client and the
API where you've got to think about the
that kind of transport security and make
sure that any data transmitted is kept
confidential and also that you've got
the
kind of integrity and knowledge that the
client is connected to the right API and
then and then you've got all the kind of
security controls at the API might want
to enforce itself so authenticating a
client to find out who they are firing
access control rules performing audit
logging and things like this to kind of
get a picture of who's doing what on the
API okay yeah so there's loads of
different scopes to the API after the
security to figure out you know what's
important to protect yeah you need to
figure out what you're protecting
fundamentally there yeah exactly so I'd
break this down into kind of a series of
steps so there's working out what
exactly are the valuable things the kind
of assets of your your API deals with so
that might be data that is confidential
it might be data about individuals that
has to be kept private and then things
like the credentials you use to
authenticate are themselves you know
things that need to be kept confidential
and then and then working out the kind
of whatever their kind of security goals
you need to achieve for your API so some
data might need to be kept confidential
other data might be public but you you
want to preserve the integrity of that
data so not just anybody should be able
to alter it or will change it and this
could be something that's done before
the API as you're designing it
throughout the life of the API or
because you've brought on a new product
or a new customer and your requirements
change or there's some external factor
from MicroStation government laws right
exactly so what all those things gonna
feed in and you should be sort of during
initial design sort of having a
consideration of what the security
aspects of something are and then sort
of reviewing those ongoing as as
requirements change and new features are
invented okay we've done a few other
shows on you mentioned api s-- with
micro services so we did
showed 370 with Chris Richardson
Richardson on micro-service patterns
showed t13 with James Lewis or
micro-services sure 337 with Ben
siegelman on distributed tracing so that
comes into this of what it logs types of
thing and then showed 210 Stefan till
cough I think it's how you pronounce it
on micro services and different
architectures and then a couple of other
shows on cloud security episode 3 1 4 3
or 9 so I'll make sure they were there
in the show notes to be referenced so
would you say with the ongoing thought
process of you know what my securing
what my protecting has anything changed
is this the same as what you would do
for a website not like a marketing
website but like a web portal our
customer watering website versus an API
that you just speak to the machines or
software so there's not a visual element
to it mm-hmm
so in terms of the kind of working out
what the kind of security goals are and
what your what's important to protect a
lot of that is very similar between a
traditional website and an API where
things get different is in the kind of
diversity of different clients you have
to serve as an API so you know with a
website traditional website the the
website is controlling both the UI the
user interface and kind of back-end
processing and so it can enforce
security through through specific
mechanisms whereas with an API you've
got different clients which are going to
access your API in different ways and so
you have to come up with more general
mechanisms so to take an example of you
know a traditional web application you'd
be thinking about was sometimes called C
surf CSRF attacks around cookies
and there's lots of cross-site request
forgery that's right and this is where
you know you set a cookie in your
browser whatever that allows your user
to access your system but if they then
browse to another website that website
can start making requests to your system
and your browsers just gonna send the
cookie along
those requests as well and so the
website might be able to do things that
that you don't want it to be able to do
and traditionally in it you know web
application you'd solve this with I
would have called an T CSRF token so you
generate a token and you include that as
a hidden field in all the forms you
generate on your on your website and
then you check that that's there when
you submit it so that that works on a
traditional website because the website
is both generating those forms and
processing them whereas with an API the
user interfaces generating forms or
input is whatever the client wants it to
be and so the API doesn't have this the
same level of control so that the
mechanisms you'd use would be would be
slightly different in that case do you
think you're doing double the work when
you do web portal versus an API as an
aside I personally find it nice of
working with api's than a web portal you
can't just assume as a user logging into
the website right you it might be trying
to be used as an API is being used right
so you've got to think about two
potential ways that your web poll is
being used but if you're just doing an
API you do you not just have to think
about it being used by software yes
exactly so you're right before api's
were common you know there was a lot of
this kind of scraping that that went on
where there were kind of people who
wanted to write programs to access data
on your website whenever it booth force
to kind of load the HTML and then pause
it and try to figure out which bits are
the the actual data yeah I've done that
myself all right yeah you know I'm sure
most developers have have been paid to
do that at some point in their life and
it's it's difficult for the developer
writing that and then it's also
difficult for the people you know
running the service because this they
can't distinguish these clients from
normal users or maybe they can through
you know log analysis and things but so
by extracting API and kind of making it
clear that there is this programmatic
interface that you can access it kind of
allows you to kind of realize that not
all of your users will be actually users
some of the movie B programs and so you
can be a lot clearer about the sorts of
ways your API might be accessed in the
kind of security risks and like they
involve about not showing the correct
term and security parlance but the
security landscape or attack surface is
small or any API or bigger than a web
portal would you say so
well we normally talk about the attack
surface and also the the kind of threat
model which is about about the kind of
threats so potentially they're pretty
similar but with with the UI there are
specific attacks against you is that you
don't have to worry about within with an
API so well you worry about them less so
for instance if you're writing a web UI
you might worry a lot about cross-site
scripting attacks where somebody is
gonna try and inject JavaScript into
your your UI to then control it to
perform it malicious actions whereas
with an API you know you're serving
typically something like Jason or
whatever and there are some ways that
that can be exploited against web
browser clients but the author of the
API you mostly don't have to worry about
that okay and the security testing tools
example like burp suite where that would
sit as an intermediate proxy between
your browser and your run tasks for you
to actions and a recorder and then it
plays the back tool could be used to
validate your API as well yeah it offers
as an Internet testing tool yeah and
things like perhaps wheat and so on you
know move with the times and have you
know specific kind of API testing
facilities built into them now as well
so they can they can do all kinds of
things from kind of automated scanning
looking for common vulnerabilities and
this kind of you know interactive things
that have penetration tests and we do
kind of yeah you know sort of
interactively exploring an API and then
trying replaying requests and doing
what's called fuzzing where you kind of
start with a request and then to sort of
random variations of it to try and see
if if any of those produce anomalous
output it sounds like that's price and
other matter work you need to do whether
saw web portal and if you actually put
got their unique elements to security
yeah I guess do they do still need to
care about SQL injection on both of them
yeah definitely you would I mean
injection is is Torelli the OWASP top 10
of kind of yeah that infamous yeah
that's famous not infamous yes so that's
the kind of top 10 security
vulnerabilities and injection so
covering both you know sequel injection
and LDAP injection of those things is is
the top top issue there and it's always
and it's the same for API so if your API
is taking requests from the user and
clearing a database to produce API
results then you still have to worry
about that so all the same advice of
using you know prepared statements and
things than that would would apply to an
API yeah and still arm you've got a key
value and that of JSON that gets posted
or URL parameter whether that comes in
from the browser or not it's all the
same type of technique isn't it yeah
okay I'd like to go through some
specific examples that I found taken
from your book I'm sorry regardless of
what the API is exposing service-wise
your upcoming book API security and
action stage security should consist of
rate limiting which is used to prevent
users on the web overwhelming your API
over the crests and limiting than our
service threats
encryption which ensures the data is
kept confidential and sent to or from
your API information disclosure
it also offers potentially proof of
integrity authentication which we've
touched on and detail the last show but
that makes sure users or consumers of
your API or one
their term or who they are say they are
and the spoofing access control and
authorization so are they allowed to do
the thing they're asking to do and then
I would probably save from a business
point of view and a debug point of view
your order login is one of the most sort
of powerful things that you can do which
I'd like to dig in quite deep wait
you're on mm-hmm
I missed anything in those them but I
know you've got a big big book that
covers a lot but I'm not going to
discuss encryption much today but was
anything really important I missed and
that left and now I think you covered
them all so those would be the main sort
of security controls or security
mechanisms that you'd want to enforce um
and they come from kind of analysis of
the kind of threats that are typical for
an API so touched on threatened modeling
earlier and one of the most common sort
of approaches to threat modeling is this
stride acronym which kind of there's a
kind of way of thinking about
systemically kind of different threats
to a general software system not just
api's but so there's spoofing tampering
pewdie ation is the always the tricky
one which means sort of denying that you
did something information disclosure
denial of service and elevation of
privilege so those mechanisms we talked
about a kind of addressing those threat
categories in a kind of systematic way
so okay and that would apply to anything
that not just an API yeah yeah I'm
actually gonna bring up that term a bit
later on in the show but it's good that
came up now to give everyone a heads up
so I'm not I haven't listed encryption
as something we're going to dig in today
briefly could you explain why we need it
with an example of how you do it but
should be perfect so encryption it's
kind of used in two main areas within an
API so the most prominent one is the
transport layer security between a
client and the
API and there you're talking about SSL
or TLS so in terms of a REST API that
normally be HTTP so secure HTTP most
websites now are moving to this and
almost all API so I would expect to have
a CH yes as a baseline and the reason
it's is needed is firstly to protect the
confidentiality of the data flowing
between the API and the client so the
client might be on an insecure network
or whatever there might be other clients
there that you don't want to have to
have access to data so you use the
encryption there to prevent the data
being snooped on but then also the other
main thing that HBS provides is
integrity of that data as well so if you
all say you've got the Dropbox client on
your phone say and you're in an airport
on airport Wi-Fi and you one download
one of your files it's going to talk to
the Dropbox API to download that file
and it might be even that you you don't
care particularly about the
confidentiality of that file but you
want to know that the father you get on
your phone is the same file that came
off Dropbox of servers and nobody could
have tampered with it in the way or
substituted a different different phone
so that's that's the other key aspect of
HTTP is that it's predicting that
integrity as well so can I just
interrupt there how would that if you're
downloading the file through HTTP was
encrypted how does that a file gap file
dated other than it's the session start
with Dropbox mm-hmm how do you validate
that that is the file that it's supposed
to be is that not like a hashing the
file to check is right and that's that
within this region there are this is
this is what HTTP or TLS does for you is
that it as well as encrypting so if it
does what's called authenticated
encryption so it'll use what's a keyed
hash known as a message authentication
code or Mac so as well as encrypting is
also macking this this data which means
both both sides know the same key and so
they can both encrypt and decrypt data
and they can also then verify these
message authentication codes and make
sure that somebody without the key
couldn't couldn't compute a valid
message authentication code so they
can't yeah man in the middle attack okay
hmm right exactly
so this kind of it ensures the kind of
integrity of data flow and then the
other key aspect with HTTP is that when
you connect dropbox dropbox is going to
authenticate itself to your client using
your certificates you know you really
have connected to dropbox yes the
dropbox will do the server client type
keymod off of HTTP where most other
systems just care the other speaking to
the right so our or service and that
server our service might not check the
client and the client might not per
server certificate to treat us these
kind of confidentiality and integrity
things they only rely on authenticating
the server so the transport layer you
know so long as the client connection to
server service proves that it really is
dropbox calm or whatever using its
certificate and then whether or not the
client authenticates is kind of up to
the server and its policy of how it's
going to control access to things but
for the the transport layer just
authenticating the server ease is enough
because the the client that's connected
to the server and so once it's
established its connecting to the right
so then everything else is kind of
secure from that point ok but actually
so that's a part of the HTTP protocol
okay so in my head would you need to you
would need to think about that in the
file that you've requested to be
downloaded once it's on your PC or
laptop you don't need to care got us and
all the father you think is yeah I mean
who's the only yeah so that's Dropbox
this job isn't right
exactly when you store your files within
Dropbox they will take care of storing
them securely
I have no insider knowledge of how they
do that okay yeah that's a whole
different topic of sort of file
validation for example you know when you
don't download clinics distribution or a
DVD or a big files you should go char
some file that you can validate it's
actually not be tampered with but that's
not what we're talking about here so
like to move on to event occasion access
control and authorization that was
pretty much the gist of my last show and
what i worth - is there anything not
using OAuth to an open ID Connect that
you'd like to mention in relation to
what people call the three days to
authentication of access control and
authorization with regards to those so I
think I'll rephrase if you're not going
to use oauth2 what do you use right for
most API is probably using oauth2 is a
good style by the way okay
but so there are there are a few
different things so if you're writing an
API that's primary job is to serve a
traditional web application right and
you don't anticipate it ever needing to
deal with you know mobile clients or
devices or whether services and so then
you could just go ahead and use
traditional cookies you know obsession
cookies that you'd use on the website
and that can be fine for your own API
that kind of really easy to use you know
most frameworks and clients know how to
use cookies and you get advantages you
know that the browser will only send the
cookie to the right website and you can
mark that as secure so they make sure
you don't accidentally send them over
over a normal secure Channel so that
would that be where you're logging into
a portal and that portal has got you
authenticate and create that the session
cookie cookie sorry
and then the JavaScript on that page is
assuming the API yeah exactly
so you're not talking about writing some
software that creates a session cookie
and presents that in the next if you had
had it as a thunderkick no right so
we're talking about and so like a
browser-based apps then
single page app would be the tradition
of fiancée you go to your website it
load some JavaScript you log in you get
a session cookie as you would on a
traditional web app and then the
JavaScript is making API calls to your
server and the browser is just going to
include the cookie on those just like
you were yes that's in the context of a
rage already isn't it yeah right so in
that case you that like a traditional
web app you have to worry about you know
C server tax that we talked about
earlier and things like that but
otherwise it's kind of transparent but
got not be only if the JavaScript on the
page is speaking to the same domain or
hostname right because if it goes to
another one then the course would kick
in wouldn't it yeah so if it goes to if
you didn't if you're making cross-domain
requests then yeah you have to get
across origin request or something
there's an ax cross origin resource
sharing I think it's there and so so
with that you can return headers to say
yes I'm gonna allow you know my API
running on say google.com is going to
allow requests from youtube.com and so
the google.com would return head is
saying that that's fine and the browser
would allow those requests whereas
normally it would block them so with
cookies that becomes quite more painful
because there's quite a lot of extra
headers you have to include it cause to
get browsers to actually send cookies on
custom-made and particularly to ya if
you're using it in a browser than
Firefox or Chrome or complain because
it's not the place you're connecting to
mm-hmm turn the place you're connecting
to your house to present those headers
like you just said yeah to say oh yeah I
allow you to come in and get that but if
they don't do if the the back-end
service API doesn't present them or
check them you could easily just write
something yourself to speak to the API
and course does matter does it
right exactly so yeah it's mainly with
these cookies so cookies a nice and easy
when you're everything's on the same
same sort of
to Maine as soon as you kind of go
beyond that so either kind of do it
costume a and stuff or talking about
mobile apps or IOT devices or whatever
then they become sort of increasingly
more clumsy as as you go on so the main
alternative then is North to and sending
a token in a in a header so normally
you'd send a token in the authorization
header with a it's got the bearer
authorization scheme yeah in HTTP which
was designed for OAuth 2 but people use
it outside earth to tow that's part of
the Hoth to spec isn't yeah
and that token is either something that
you you look to spec for like the last
two or you traitor than yourself right
and there's a bunch of different ways so
so all the two kind of leaves it
unspecified the format of the tokens for
all the two access tokens so it's keep
people commonly used JSON web tokens
John's for this but there are other
things so lots of people as well use you
know database server side tokens where
it's stored in a database is it much
like a session cookie would be and the
token is just a short random string can
I just ask a quick question everyone
cause a GWT or JSON web token a jot
mm-hmm my being really silly yeah why I
called the job I don't know where it
comes from I think it I think it says it
in the spec I can't remember but but
it's certainly it's the pronounciation
that everyone's kind of agreed on but
it's just what it means yeah
ja ja tis JWT yeah all right okay
that's clear that yeah so the tokens are
jots are often used for for tokens so
you can use them outside of oauth2 and
you can just you can create a joke and
send it to the API and the API will kind
of validate that job but then there's
these other kind of token formats people
use so some people use just some
frameworks have have kind of basic kind
of authenticated encryption so you just
you create a JSON object with some
details about the user or whatever who's
logged in and then you just encrypt that
blob using something like well we took
that might in Episode II a Muslim about
that which is kind of a I kind of
standard cryptography library the lots
of people recommend and it's just got
this kind of encrypt decrypt there's no
options no kind of choices whereas with
jots there's like a million options is
there somewhere we we can point
listeners to to go and reference and
read to say right I've decided that or
on a token to use what's the recommended
type the took on our encryption he just
mentioned blip solely sodium there so
people don't have to leave matter what
we all think about this where we do
direct and I was at your book but yeah
you can't have bound by my book first so
there is a bunch of different things I
guess so if you're if you're going to
use jobs than job I oh so January t2 IO
is the kind of main website I guess
which has links to a bunch of different
client libraries and documentation and
things about about jobs for various
different programming languages
personally if I was just kind of if I
didn't have to interoperate with other
systems and was just producing you know
getting an IPA API to produced login
token say that that only that API itself
is going to consume then yeah definitely
look at something like nip so do you can
just go to I think it's just lip sodium
dog that has bindings so that's a
cryptographic library it has bindings
for most languages okay I'm going to use
would you put anything in that talk on
ours are just a global unique strength
that you would save in the database
somewhere and have some other mate it
mattered data to associate that with a
user you can either go it depends how
you how you wanted so the kind of safest
thing to do is to put some data into a
database so you know create a session in
a database table or use a product that
will do this for you and stall the
details in there and then your token
then can just be some random identifier
which is the primary key of that
entering the database like a normal
session cookie
right so the some people sort of don't
like that because it kind of limits the
scalability to a certain degree because
you've got this database that has to be
looked up every time you want to check
of is in the session and you've got
potentially a central point of failure
you know both of those can be overcome
you know databases now are pretty good
at scaling and doing failover and
recovery and things a lot of people then
move towards something like jaws or
encrypted chase and objects where where
you would instead of putting that data
in a database you just create a JSON
object which contains you know here's
the user here's maybe what what you know
groups they're in what what roles they
have perhaps in your API here's an
expiry time for this token and then you
take all that and kind of encrypt it and
authenticated like you know like we were
talking about before so you use this
authenticated encryption where you're
both hiding the contents of the data and
ensuring that it's it's valid and can't
be tampered with and then you give that
to the client and then you don't have to
store anything at all on the server side
you can just go so you've got some type
of scalability there because you've got
a sort of a black hole there of session
denial of service good well I think it
used to be a case went to displace was
you know a limiting factor but you could
have some rule client keep on praying
and use sessions and you sessions and
you sessions right that could be a over
yeah and you can you can prevent that
via you know kind of rate limiting your
your API and preventing clansmen
creating too many sessions but with the
kind of jots model everything's on the
client so all the client is doing is
getting you to create new tokens and
there's nothing stored on the server so
is there a thought process where you
think well if I'm doing an encrypted jar
is not more overhead encrypting and
decrypting and then a session based
database lookup right right you know
depend on the algorithm you pick you
know there's a trade-off there or is it
so fast there is definitely a trade-off
there so if your database in your API
servers are in the same data center
you know typically then then actually
you know a round trip to your database
is going to be pretty pretty quick and
is there's a kind of with dots you'd
kind of if you're doing what would call
symmetric cryptography so using either a
yes or a CH Mac as their as they're
known as the algorithms where the person
producing the token and the person the
API consuming the token have the same
key so that's why we call it symmetric
they have the st. key that's usually
pretty quick and it and it's it's can
often be quicker than a roundtrip with
newer your data center especially
because most server hardware will have
hardware acceleration for IES and things
on that where it changes as if a lot of
people start using Johnson and they
start using public key cryptography like
RSA and often that's not really cool for
because it's small within a closed
ecosystem you could share a key but in
public key cryptography you have a
separate public key and a private key
and those public key algorithms are
typically a lot more expensive than than
symmetric ones you know sort of orders
of magnitude more more it's been sifted
there'll be the same technology as when
you sign an email with PGP or can you PG
or something right exactly
wait where you publish your public key
and then people go and look it up and
they encrypt more sign e Mountain yeah
so if you're if you're using say RSA
signatures to sign a jot which you're
giving to an API client and every time
it sends it back you've got to verify
that signature that's that can get
really expensive we talked about you
know TLS before the TLS uses public key
cryptography but he only uses it for a
very short period an initial handshake
and then it kind of negotiate its shared
keys for that session after that and
does symmetric crypto from then on
because public key crypto is just too
expensive
so you want to do it as little as
possible and I suppose the the jaw I'm
never gonna get used to saying job but I
suppose the job would be quite big as
well once it's got these encryption
right it would be the encrypted jaw has
got five sections and the normal ones
got three separated by periods or full
stops right with with the symmetric
cryptography though I was talking about
so you know what do you want to use
what's called authentication encryption
and I've talked about so both in Crips
and authenticates so it hides the data
inside the top and it and it prevents
its being tampered with when you move to
the public key algorithms public key
encryption algorithms don't do that they
just they just encrypt they just hide
the data and they don't guarantee
authentication so what you end up having
to do with dots then is you you first
sign a job which creates one job and
then you encrypt that wrapping it in
another jot so you end up with this
nested thing where the inner the inner
job is is signed using RSA signatures or
whatever and then you encrypt it in an
outer job and you get these nested
things and they can get pretty big I've
seen the RFC for those when I was
looking at charts obviously there's been
a demand for them because an RFC and
it's gone through the working groups to
process it would be the primary user of
such complicated tokens well they're
used in a variety of places so a lot of
people want this kind of just give me an
encrypted blob of JSON right and John
says the standard way to do that so a
lot of people think well I have to use
jaws but in reality there are there are
easy ways like the lip sodium where like
people just take care of all that for
you
just then have a lot of a lot of options
and a lot of flexibility for different
use cases and so they they tend to then
be used in standards that need a lot of
flexibility as well so Open ID Connect
for instance that you mentioned before
and you talk about with just in richer
that uses mandates the use of jots for
ID tokens there and that's because these
ID tokens are designed for
interoperability between systems so
they need to use a standard and those
systems might support different
cryptographically cryptographic
algorithms and things mandate higher are
lower levels and yeah okay I'd like to
move on to another section but briefly
before we switch what's the difference
between authorization and access control
so the way they use mostly they're
they're kind of synonyms and they're
both kind of around controlling who has
access to to what within a system there
is a kind of distinction between them in
the authorization is is something that
that people do so if I have a document
on Dropbox say and I want to grant you
access to it then then I would be
authorizing you to have access to that
and then access control is the mechanism
by which Dropbox is going to enforce
that those those rooms that I've set are
actually enforced so it could be two
stages you could come along and see I
might offer eyes to access this resource
yes no and then the access control is
what you're allowed to do once you've
been authorized to access well of course
right yes so you might have so
authorization is kind of a process that
you're when you join a company your
system administrator might you know
authorize you to to access various
systems that you need to or various
api's for your job and then they're
going to they're going to actually do
that by setting the access control rules
within the software ever the NuForce
that it's a difference between it kind
of pretty similar yeah all right okay
I'm going to switch this on to
rate-limiting and briefly touched on
this or the starless sure but you can
you read to find what real limiting is
from an API point of view right so so
great limiting is protection against
this kind of denial of service attacks
so if some client is trying to overwhelm
your API with jiminee requests or
sending data too quickly or or whatever
rate little bit rate limiting then is a
way to kind of get them to slow down and
so you can define rules with
your API they're gonna say you know say
per IP address you can only issue you
know 20 requests per minute or something
like that and after that I'm gonna
either disconnect you from the API or
I'm going to start what's called the
throttling so I'm gonna start processing
your request more slowly and making you
slow down in that that way
so rate limiting is often not done
within the API itself is often done at a
kind of layer ahead of the API so you'd
have like a what's called a reverse
proxy or you might do it at a load
balancer layer and lots of cloud
services like Amazon and Google and
stuff will offer load balancer services
that will do some kind of basic rate
limiting for you so it's just kind of
Kenya preventing your API getting
overwhelmed by kind of malicious
requests so you'd be protecting it from
malicious requests but also badly
designed clients or your own systems
that might not know what they're doing
and just write exactly in a big week
someone yeah so yeah you know if you've
got a misconfigured client that's
failing you know that's been configured
to retry requests that fail but it's
it's it's not it's not noticing that the
request has succeeded right in my end up
in the loop where it's just me trying a
quest yeah over and over again so I
presume if if you're designing the API
or you've got an API you could outsource
this element if it's a cloud service to
protect your API and then leave it off
for some type of API you consume to
validate that it's not being breached
mm-hmm or quite a few years in you won't
care that would probably have an API
that you need to check but then you
wouldn't see the request anyway because
if we drop to another yeah so typically
it's either the request is either
dropped or depending on how you're
designing your system you might queue up
requests and kind of process them later
or you might just just block the request
and you know send your response later on
so there is HTTP has some kind of
specialized
return codes for this so you can return
loneliness of four to nine which is too
many requests or something and you can
set ahead of them which is retry after
that you can say okay yes so you can use
this pattern right see more I can say no
with your Dropbox example that they
include how many requests you've got
left are they in that headed right yeah
so yeah you can do that so there's you
can provide hints to a client so there's
different ways as well that rate
limiting is done and it could be a bit
confusing so there's kind of a kind of
simple level of rate limiting that has
done often right at the edge of your
your network where typically that's just
based on the IP address of the client
and you just kind of say a flat you know
you can't know IP address can have more
than 100 requests a minute or whatever
and so the basic protection rights hours
and then you might have you know after
after the client hasn't logged in and
you're able to know who they are you
might have quotas associated with their
account which say we're actually for you
know business reasons or whatever you
you've only paid for you know a thousand
requests a month or something a purely
commercial decision to say right we need
a commercial model for this API it's
gonna be free but you can only do so
much right and they're they're kind of
related but from a security point of
view it's mostly that kind of rate
limiting right on the edge of trying to
stop request consuming resources in your
system too too quickly so you don't want
so the three main security goals to put
termina get talked about you know sort
of software security are what's known as
the CIA triad it's often courses we've
already talked about confidentiality and
integrity in terms of encryption and
then the a is availability so when I was
one academic CIA
I said yeah like the American see right
exactly so it's kind of easy to to
remember so confidentiality integrity
and then availability so the
rate-limiting you're trying to allow
preserve availa
legitimate users and legitimate clients
of your API can always access it and
somebody can't overwhelm the API with
bogus requests then gonna stop
legitimate users accessing it yeah for
example I have think in the Dropbox API
another API is I've seen when you're
requesting resource that changes you
might want to populate the response with
if modified since so when you're
requesting a list of something each at
that header to see if it's changed if it
has to go off and request the whole lot
and the back anything returns new
records in the resource but if it hasn't
since the last time you've looked and it
doesn't need to send it where so anyone
that doesn't read the docs properly and
doesn't use that header might just pull
the system every second and that's a
sort of client you might want to drop
and read on that yeah exactly so yeah
so it's not just malicious clients but
people yeah people lazy developers I
guess who you are who are reading the
documentation and I remember when I was
when I was younger I used to read
slashed off I don't know if you did as
well but smashed on the sort of news
website and I remember they they had a
introduced a kind of the early version
of like an RSS feed right the night and
I remember writing some kind of client
that was gonna pull that and I display
these slash top articles and yeah I
think I got banned within about an hour
because I just left this thing running
in it hadn't realized it was like
spamming the requests it's often why is
my PC zipper CPU so high and slow you
know so yeah how glad you might mention
to see I try that so has covered that so
really limiting I would understand it to
go as deep as you want so it could be
the network level of the appliance level
country level routing protocols DNS all
that type of thing but if you just want
some basic protection is it something
you would implement yourself is that
simple or would you look to something in
the framework that you're doing or you
know
what would you recommend I guess most
api's that are going to be big enough
for this to be able to worry that they
might they might be attacked in this way
are gonna have some kind of reverse
proxies or load balancers you know these
are the kind of basic parts of a
deployment of an API and almost all of
those now come with some kind of basic
rate limiting for example of the micro
service I would have that built in as
well that's exposing a container
wouldn't it right exactly so if you look
at same communities right you've got
these called ingress controllers which
are handling like traffic coming in and
that's basically a kind of reverse proxy
and you know that I think the official
ones using nginx nginx has great
limiting options built in and then you
can use like I say most of the cloud
service providers like AWS and Google
cloud platform will have some kind of
load balancer service which will have
some kind of rate limiting options built
into it so it's not a big decision to
make at the start or something right
exactly so unlike like if you get that
big customer we spoke about you can put
something in later on right exactly it's
it's of all the kind of security
controls we talked about it's the one
that is most easy to kind of defer and
delegate to to some other component and
just use an off-the-shelf solution for
it okay
in this section I've taken a note of the
strike a comment that we touched on
earlier in the show do you want to just
go through that again
how about applies to rate limiting mm-hm
so yes so stride is an approach to
what's called threat modeling so threat
modeling is is looking at your API
looking at your system and trying to
work out the ways it could be attacked
not necessarily things that are real but
just looking at it as a system
architecture and saying well you know
somebody might want to tamper with this
part or you know break into this bit or
whatever and stride then is is a way
that was come up with as a kind of
systematic way of identifying those
threats by breaking them down into
categories and so stride sands for
spoofing which is pretending to be
somebody else that you you know if your
malicious user pretending to be a
legitimate user of the API tampering so
you know chain altering data that that's
being served by the API or somehow
messing with the integrity of the system
repudiation is the are which is so
that's kind of denying that you did
something so being able to kind of
perform a malicious action and then deny
that was you that did that later on
information disclosure is kind of
gaining access to information that you
should have access to so this is kind of
undermining the privacy or
confidentiality of the system and then
denial of service which is which is the
one most related to rate limiting which
is which is what we talked about so this
is kind of overwhelming the API with
request so that legitimate users can't
gain access but there's a there's other
forms of denial of service as well so
you know if you can just crash the
server and take it offline then that
would never in turn also deny other
people them access and then the last one
is elevation of privilege which is you
know if you've got a legitimate account
to access an API you might be able to
upgrade the permissions of your account
to say an admin level permissions when
you shouldn't be able to and then you
can do more on the system than you
should be able to do ok that brings us
on to the next section but a quite
interested to explore elevation of
privilege and what you see in the API
ecosystem of how that is possible if we
take the Dropbox one you know what
how would that manifest yourself right
so there's there's a bunch of different
ways that this this might be possible
usually when the API is not is not
properly enforcing access control checks
on the server so commonly you see this
where you've got a bunch of like admin
only api's
and the person who's designed the system
has kind of assumed that nobody will
guess the URL under which those things
and so it's just checking have you got a
session at all or not checking whether
you're whether you've got an admin
session and so because they haven't
documented the admin API so whatever
they assume that nobody's gonna do them
and so somebody who's got a you know a
normal account then can just change the
URL on the requests that they're making
and suddenly start performing admin only
operations they would need to figure out
what discover maybe a random URL that
they've created right I mean usually
these are not that random right I've got
some type of random string name or
something put in here the other thing
which is kind of related to that is
where a user might have an API to access
their own resources which is under you
know slash users slash knee or whatever
and then I can just again just change
that URL to slash users slash Gavin and
suddenly I'm accessing your resources
right so it's not the server is not
enforcing the you know I should only
have access to Neil's resources and it's
the kind of suing that just because the
URL is correct that that's enough to
keep people out
yeah Lester's will be able to see by
this myelin right now because I remember
doing that on my own API at some point
in the design but luckily I brought ask
to check you know is the authenticated
user able to change the name to someone
else because you'd usually forget that
you know right and this is this is
something that crops up within with to
sometimes as well in the model of
authorization in oauth2 is delegated
authorization so kind of you know you've
got an account system you've access to
something and you want to let some
third-party your mobile app access your
files on Dropbox whatever right and so
you can grant it an oauth2 token that
says you know you this app has gotten
read-only access to my files and that's
kind of the scope of the token says what
about token allows access to but a lot
of people then implement OAuth 2 and
thing
the scopes is is all they need to check
to allow access they don't then check
that the resource owner the person
improve the token would actually have
access to the thing themselves and so
again you know you so you might have an
app that was given you know that I
authorized an access token with you know
read-only scope for Dropbox a it's in my
app and it can access my files but again
it might just be able to change the URL
to access Gavin's files and if Dropbox
was only checking the scope okay well
you know read-only access I'm only
giving it read-only access so that's
fine right but but I by myself shouldn't
have access to your files so there's
sometimes cops like an API around there
so yeah it needs some type of base class
that checks the checks they should be
checking first before it does the next
one - yeah it should always be so well
off - OH - scope should always be an
additional check on top of your normal
access control checks it's not a
replacement for traditional kind of
permission based access control it's a
it's a layer on top okay yeah it comes
down to good design doesn't it and I'm
thinking from the good point good side
of things and the bad side of things as
well
yeah I want to move on to just getting
close to the end of the show now to the
word that I can't say repudiation or
good for that yeah which is the order
log so I'd like to move on to the final
section of our order logs which from an
Operations point of view and security
point of view is probably the most
important part of an API would you say
yep definitely I would say if there was
one thing to concentrate on with an API
is making sure you've got good looks and
and good log monitoring in place whether
it's a web portal an API wherein the
request response cycle should the order
log be performed right in the front with
the rate-limiting or you know everywhere
I have to say yeah so you normally you
want for audit logging you don't want it
quite as on the edge as rate limiting
because
you want it to happen after
authentication so you know who the user
is and so you know the user
authenticates and then and then you're
gonna log about them and the important
thing with audit logs is to log attempts
at performing actions so sometimes
people only audit log successful
operations and they do that after the
operations completed successfully and
that that's a mistake because you you
want to be able to see what people are
trying to do on your system not
necessarily what they actually did so
it's often you know requests that get
rejected but uh the first signs of
somebody trying to start attack because
you know they're trying every possible
password for this user or whatever so
this this relates to the authentication
what I was saying so all day long you
can happen after authentication but you
need to be careful then not to reject
requests because they fail to
authenticate so you still want to log
those as well so if somebody tries to
log in but types in their own password
so you should log successful or
unsuccessful attempt yeah so you can do
this kind of one two ways as well you
you can even log separately so you log
when the request comes in you log in the
request has come in and then separately
when the response goes back out again
you log another log event saying and
this was the the outcome you know the
the request you know succeeded or it
failed for some reason and then you
typically have some kind of ID that kind
of links up those two log events or you
can you can wait until the end and then
log it just at the end of the request
which runs the risk then that say the
service crashes or something like that
and then you lose that that log event
this is kind of similar to acid
transactions and databases and somewhere
we touched on in my LM TV show with
Howard where you've got to think about
that transaction doing you because it is
a transaction you're doing with the log
it is yeah but you need to be careful as
well not to connect it with your your
business logic transaction so I had
actually made this mistake in a system i
I
meant to die imprinted the audit longing
for a system a long time ago and we had
this it was a big kind of EJB java
enterprise app what cjp enterprise
javabean so this is kind of you know
sort of what still still reasonable use
but it used to be the big 2002 properiy
exactly so and this system was kind of
request would come in and then it would
do a load of database transactions
within a distributed transaction manager
thing and then I would log an audit
event when it completed but because of
the way EJ B's work I hadn't realized
that that that logging the event which
was going to a database would then get
joined onto the same transaction as
everything else which meant that if the
requests failed that transaction got
rolled back and the audit log also got
rolled back with it yeah which is why
you don't want to do that because that
means you know these these fails
requests which are often from security
point of view the most interesting ones
you know when somebody's trying to do
something and failing repeatedly all of
those were getting lost because they
were just being brought back with
everything else and of course I was
picked up in your tests oh yeah yeah of
course yeah okay so yeah with the order
log in rather than you and I try and
come up with a format as though were a
place we could go that will tell us what
we need to log on how yeah so there's
some there are some sort of standards
around audit logging I don't know if
they go into the detail of exactly where
you should log so there's things like
ISO 27001 which is a kind of big
standard this often people you have kind
of regulatory requirements to secure the
systems will implement this as opposed
to securing responders right yeah so
particularly you know if you do anything
to do with financial services you'll
probably be familiar with this yeah
and that has that has sections on you
know
logging in-house protecting logs and and
is this how are we talking about advent
log in here or is it auto log-in it so
yes I audit logging I would to people
often refer to audit logging also using
the term like security event logging as
kind of related things so there's this
kind of access logs have kind of you
know who's who's accessing your system
and what's going on and then there might
be you might have specific event logs
for say somebody's just changed their
password or something like that so
things that are particularly security
kind of sensitive events and then yeah
so there's this ISO standard NIST as
well ever have a standard espy 800 - 92
I think it is rocky I'll get that yep so
they kind of cover you know what you
should be logging how you should be
logging it certificate they'll say you
know you should be centralizing
collection of your logs so you know you
can log to your local disk but you
should be periodically scraping those
logs and sending them to a central
service yeah sure I mean would you
recommend putting the logs into like
something like elastic starch there was
a finite lifespan or is it more critical
than that
so you would yeah so you'd normally a
lot of people would recommend you know
putting your logs into what's called a
CMS IEM security it's making an event
management so there's a whole bunch of
these Splunk use out stack so thats
elasticsearch log stash and compiler
there's a bunch of these tools then
which will kind of suck in logs form all
your systems across your whole kind of
idea state so it guys and everything
else you made sure they were set up to
not just recycle them every seven days
and we'd have to keep a permanent
storage right and they yeah you could
set policies around that on kind of log
retention and how
they're gonna keep you around for those
things then will typically be you know
pressing the logs and displaying in a
way that you can kind of review them
manually but then also you can you can
attach automated processes to those kind
of looking what's called doing kind of
anomaly detection so they're looking for
who's out with the ordinary behavior
that might might indicate an attack is
happening and then they might generate
an alert yeah so you might have so I
might have the Dropbox example where you
get an email or a notification to say
we've just approved to have our log in
from somewhere else
right exactly so yes so it's similar
kind of thing there so yeah my inner
layer going out to be users saying you
know somebody's just changed your
password from this IP address was that
new similar things within within within
an organization you might have you know
a security team who are gonna get paged
at 3:00 a.m. if there's a you know
there's a high so the activities
happened and it's been long after the
fact or something else is picked up but
this is yeah not normal yeah like you
know a system administrator changing his
password at you know 3:00 a.m. you know
that's not that's not particularly
normal you know so you know things like
that it might pick up and say somebody
needs to look at this so the logs would
need to be accessible from something
that can more to them and look for
things that are important to the
business or the application they would
need to be part of our consumable to
show potentially the user what's been
happening so they know if something's
changed they can look at those logs and
uh you know a trimmed-down version and
plus they up to team what security you
need to be able to search and get access
to everything so that's the sort of
place you'd have to think about yeah
it's a certificate yeah you want to have
you know the who what and how kind of
questions answered by the log so you
know the timestamp of when something
occurred you know
who was doing it what they were trying
to do was it successful or not so could
we come up with four things that should
be in an audit largest so we've got
something to work with
yeah so there should be there should be
a time stamp there should be a so if
it's like HTTP API then you'd want the
the request path that they were trying
to do and maybe the HTTP method of what
they were trying to do the the username
of the user who so that would be the
action right there's that case or what
what what they were trying to do the
username if they're you know if somebody
has logged in at this point if they're
anonymous then then leave out and
whether it's successful basically so you
might log the HTTP HTTP return code you
know status code afterwards so you know
200 okay or something about that things
you don't want to have in the logs
typically or any kind of credentials or
anything so sometimes people made a
mistake if like oh just log everything
and just dump the whole or request yeah
like a whole Jason yeah hey well then
you might end up with people's passwords
or or access tokens or whatever in the
logs and that's that's you know so you
should be quite selective about what you
log should you log like transactional
logs should it show what you what the
thing was or the object say it's a
database called a bargain should you log
what the rule was before I was changed
and why it failed or you know what the
big privacy concerns around your logs
typically not you just say somebody
changed this this thing depending on
your system you might have kind of
version control anyway you might have
you know rather than somebody just being
able to just change a database table and
the old versions lost forever you might
you might just as a kind of you know a
business continuity thing you might you
might want to kind of
have store a kind of version table of
previous versions so you can you can
roll back or go back to two previous
versions right yeah because you might
want to say for example because this is
something I know about somebody changes
where their numbers call forwarded to
but they didn't do it so they want to go
back in and see another member the team
changed it what was it before right so
that's why I was trying to get to you
know and sure though she should be to be
a historic trail of what it was
yeah and that's outside the realm of
order Ronnie yeah so you you might you
might kind of use that you kind of yeah
you have you or you need to think about
your who the intended audience for an
audit log is and what's appropriate to
be in there so you know for a system
audit log that's gonna be reviewed by
you know your security team or whatever
then you might want quite detailed one
there's an audit log showing two other
other users of the system then it may be
you know you could say Oh on Tuesday you
know Jeff changed whatever your phone
number or whatever but maybe you
wouldn't have the detail of like oh yeah
Jeff happened to be up at 3:00 a.m.
because he don't sleep or whatever yeah
we did change the audit log verbosity
depend on who's logged in
without the attorney or should you just
keep a standard yeah so typically I
guess you you would the audit log
natural log itself would be the same
although you might you might want to
have more audit logs for administrators
people with kind of elevated privileges
in the system within our own product for
instance we have sort of basic access
level kind of audit logs and then we
have you know when somebody makes this
is your open am product right yeah and
across our kind of stack so suddenly if
an administrator makes changes to
configuration that will affect you know
how the system is operating then in that
case we might log it before and after
details kind of change because we know
there's no use of passwords or whatever
in in that config
but but and it's kind of it it can have
such a huge effect on the security the
system when an administrator makes
change that that we would then you know
lot more detail in that case okay so
they should have the ability to have
more or less in that sort of action
feeling okay and I guess the for the
format's of the logs you could just have
a plain text file start off with our
database or usually while you stores
lots of things I think I think I think
so we support our bunch of different
formats and I think the most popular
wanting who uses is the JSON format
where it's kind of each line in the log
file is a JSON object so it's kind of
structured with with with detail in it
and it's kind of easy to pass yeah most
databases have a JSON binary format yeah
for a column donor so CSV would be the
other popular format all this you can
use you can log directly to something
like syslog where it's a service that's
this purpose is to gather logs over the
network and that will have a standard
format for the messages that gets into
it yeah that was something we do push
slots and test I thought that goes into
town and out stack but then you need to
be able to historically parse then and
associate that with application and
things so it's different trade-off there
isn't okay
all right I'd like to wrap up the show
know Neil and if there's one point that
you could really drive home with regards
to API security what would it be and I
think it might not rain of the hands are
there so I guess from what we've we've
just been talking about then yeah I'd
probably say say the logging really at
the moment and so it's often kind of
kind of least sexy parts I guess some
security everyone wants to concentrate
on my crypto and encryption and things
like this but really yeah having good
ordered logs and being able to get good
detail on exactly who's done what on
your system I think is is the most
important part of of API security so get
that
it will need the link back to everything
else because if you're watching the
locks and something happens you'll then
need to make a kick and rate-limiting or
you know revoke the authorization
authentication is that awake people do
yes so so yeah I mean one it's kind of
just having that visibility of your of
your system really and and yeah just
being able to without that you're kind
of completely blind and you don't know
what's what's going on in your system
and you know who's doing what so seeing
what potential attacks are happening
when when you might need to you know PI
rate limiting and then also see you know
if your authentication services failed
and every request is coming through
without using the name attached to it
and you know that's gonna alert you that
something's gone wrong there as well so
yeah definitely the most important thing
get the logs right yeah it's not like
you say it's not a sexy aside so I
bought from a security point of view
yeah that's the right way yeah so where
can people find out more you can follow
you on twitter and you've got a blog as
well yep so yet my blog is just Neil
Madden blog yeah you can follow me on
Twitter is Neil Mad Dog there was very
few usernames available when I was
looking for that yes and then you can
also the book is in early access so you
can sign up to read the first chapters
of the book online and yeah I've been a
drainer I bought it it makes me
well thank you for coming on the show
it's been a real pleasure and I wish you
all the best with completing your book
I've always wanted to write one but I
have no idea how long it takes it so
there's a lot of work but it's one of
those things once you get the idea you
know yeah yeah you want to do okay this
is Gavin Henry for software engineering
read you and thank you for listening
thank you
thanks for listening to se Radio an
educational program brought to you by
Triple E software magazine for more
about the podcast including other
episodes visit our website at SE - radio
net to provide feedback you can comment
on each episode on the website or reach
us on LinkedIn Facebook Twitter or
through our slack channel at SC
radio.com you can also email us at team
@ SC - radio net this and all other
episodes of SU radio is licensed under
Creative Commons license 2.5 thanks for
listening